[Music]
if you love haar's Belgian chocolate ice
cream I've done it two ways before this
is another really simplified way of
doing it using condensed milk stick
around and I'll show you how to do
[Music]
it super nice and simple condensed milk
version of hugar Belgian chocolate we
have our cream and our milk in
here
this is our dextrose and our cocoa
powder if you can't find the dextrose or
you don't want to go out and buy it just
use corn syrup same amount so we're
going to put that in
here and then
just slowly
combine and then we're going to open up
our condensed
milk and pour the whole thing in
to make sure we get all of
that and then just whisk that in as
well doesn't need to come up to any
specific temperature you just want to
make sure that that condensed milk is
really well
emulsified with the other ingredients so
I'd say stir it for you know four or 5
minutes now that that's all really
nicely combined we're going to take it
off the heat and put it in a container
in the fridge
overnight the Belgian chocolate base is
completely chilled now so we're going to
pop it in the ice cream machine to churn
now whilst this is happening we're going
to prepare our chocolate for this adding
we're going to do it two different ways
we're going to get our grater out as you
can see this is a calibo block of milk
chocolate which I think is about
45% Coco solid I will check and put it
up on the screen we're going to do two
things we're going to grate some of it
and we're going to chop some of it so
let's get grating as you can see this ch
chocolate is charged to hell with static
electricity don't know why if you know
how to resolve this let me know I've
never actually had this problem before
but hey first time for everything once
we've tied it up and we got all of our
shavings in a pot we're going to put
that in a freezer next we're going to
get on with the second type of chocolate
same chocolate again the calbo milk
chocolate but we're going to take some
larger pieces larger shavings and cut
them up into slightly larger chunks once
that's done put that in a container and
put that in the freezer as well finally
when the ice cream is a couple of
minutes away from being finished we're
going to start to add in all of our
chocolate you need to give this a minute
or two just to combine and then you can
load up your tubs as normal before we
put it in the freezer to completely
harden off for 2 or 3
[Music]
hours can't emphasize the importance of
the cocoa powder enough it that 7even
Hills cocoa powder has the exact same
flavor profile as the haand does one
that they use in their Belgian chocolate
so you're never going to get as close as
this is or these recipes get without
using that right cocoa powder it just
isn't one that is as close as it is I've
tried a lot of cocoa powders on this
channel none of them come anywhere near
to the flavor that the Seven Hills coca
powder does so if you want to make an
exact copy of haand dar's Belgian
chocolate Trace down 7 heels organic
cocoa powder anyway this is so good I'm
going to just sit here and eat the tub
it's like you know 2:00 on Saturday
afternoon why the hell
not thanks for much for watching don't
forget to like And
subscribe and I will see
you next
week